<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Brian Fitzgerald's Notes]]></title>
  <link href="http://Roborovskis.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Roborovskis.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-23T15:14:16-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://Roborovskis.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Fitzgerald]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[cooldude242@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Metagame in Planetside 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://Roborovskis.github.io/blog/2013/07/23/metagame-in-planetside-2/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-23T15:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Roborovskis.github.io/blog/2013/07/23/metagame-in-planetside-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Planetside 2: Making the Invisible Metagame Visible</h1>

<p>Right now, the long-term survivability of Planetside 2 is in constant question as SOE scrambles to give meaning to the endless back-and-forth deathmatch that the game currently is. War isn’t a series of long engagements between wandering zergs; what needs to be established in order to bring order and a logical sense of metagame progression is a front line, and currently, this does not exist.</p>

<pre><code>So how do we create a front line without fundamentally changing the way the game works? The answers are in the game already, for the most part.
</code></pre>

<ol>
<li><p>Make resources facility-based, not soldier-based: Right now, resources are almost completely broken. The only purpose they serve, to a player, is keep them from doing what they like- whether it’s flying a Mosquito or driving a Sunderer. In real war, it’s not the soldiers that have chunks of mineral in their pockets; what we need is a sense of a facility as something to defend, otherwise we lose the resources inside. It creates a more interesting tug-of-war that rewards defense and offense equally.</p>

<ol>
<li>So how do we divvy up the resources between players? I propose a cert tree for each type of resource- aerospace, mechanical, etc- and the more invested a player becomes, the greater share of the overall pool he can use (10%, 15%, etc..) This is also factored with the number of palyers at a station, so if 200 people are in one battle, the players with the most aerospace points are automatically given priority access. This solves problems of organization within large fights.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>Fortification- Right now we have a flat flip time across all facilities of a certain type. This is not nearly as interesting a mechanic as it could be. I propose a ‘fortification’ system that activates defenses at a base (higher walls for no light assault, increased capture time, maybe even more turrets) whenever a certain amount of enemies are nearby. Depositing resources would decrease the number of enemies required to activate this state, like so:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Level 1. 300 enemies</p></li>
<li><p>Level 2. 150 enemies</p></li>
<li><p>Level 3. 100 enemies</p></li>
<li><p>Level 4. 75 enemies</p></li>
<li><p>Level 5. 50 enemies</p></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>Bringing the fights out of the bases- Don’t get me wrong, facilities are some of the most beautiful places in the game. But I always remember the battles outside them- on a hillside protecting a sunderer under a bridge from advancing tank columns- the most vividly. Facility combat should feel like we are sieging a base, not hopping from one base to another. It should be the reward for a successful push back to the enemy’s walls.To that end I propose the following:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>More sunderer upgrades. Make sunderers mobile bases of their own, with resources and upgrades to sustain damage or deploy teleport tubes, so they can hold the line more effectively.</p></li>
<li><p>Make the facilities more spread out. I know this is kind of a big request, to change the map that drastically, but it wouldn’t kill the game to remove a few facilities, would it?</p></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>Other</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Players die WAY too fast. If gunplay is to be strategic in any sense, give us a chance to fight back from a sniper or an advancing column, instead of making it the game of whoever saw each other first wins. At least 50% more health and 25% more shield would go a long way.</p></li>
<li><p> Consecutive login rewards.</p></li>
</ol>


<p> I’ve been following this game from its announcement and over its lifespan the idealized version I had in my head and the real version have diverged significantly. Hopefully these changes will bring the visions I had of epic struggles over protecting a frontline to life. Or at least, it’ll incite discussion. Thanks for reading.</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
