<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Brian Fitzgerald</title>
<subtitle type="text">Let's talk.</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2015-04-07T10:52:29-04:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Brian Fitzgerald</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>cooldude242@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monetizing Firefox (and FOSS in general)]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/monetizing-firefox" />
  <id>/monetizing-firefox</id>
  <published>2014-09-12T12:52:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2014-09-12T12:52:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Brian Fitzgerald</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>cooldude242@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/how-do-tiles-work-firefox#w_enhanced-tiles&quot;&gt;Firefox now offers some sponsored sites in their New Tab Pages&lt;/a&gt;. After their Google affiliate revenue, this is the second method that Mozilla has developed for generating revenue from Firefox, which is otherwise a free and open source project. It’s always seemed, to me, to be a little at odds with the Mozilla ethos to gain most of their revenue from directing users to their largest competitor in the browser space, and I try to use as few ad-supported services in my daily life in possible. They seem to always dilute the experience of using a product or service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how do you harness &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.mozilla.org/press/ataglance/&quot;&gt;half a billion&lt;/a&gt; users for revenue with an open source program? It’s definitely possible. I propose the development of one solution here: a system where users donate towards specific features to be developed, towards a total estimated budget goal, out of several options that a development team can work on. I can’t imagine this hasn’t been done before, but I couldn’t find any examples. So I decided to work towards a revenue solution for this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A project’s users are able to control the direction a project goes in, even if they can’t contribute to development– and this kind of involvement might cause some onboarding of new members if they become involved enough in a project to donate money towards its development. The funds raised might go towards salaries for top developers– or possibly bug bounties for the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One difference between this setup and a crowdfunding project is that the goal here is simply a single feature or decision of a larger, already-usable product. The goals could be simply an amount of time spent on a project, rather than the promise of a single feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example: Mozilla puts up a crowdvoting system to choose between developing an embedded e-mail client or a dedicated Oculus Rift mode. The Rift mode wins out, raising $1,980,000 over $1,080,000 towards the e-mail client. The people who voted for the email client are refunded their money, and work begins on the Rift mode.
In another example, a web framework wants to hire a full time developer onto the company. So they start a fund with two options: either vote to employ a developer, or vote to put money into a Bountysource fund. The winning amount is given to the more popular vote.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/monetizing-firefox&quot;&gt;Monetizing Firefox (and FOSS in general)&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Brian Fitzgerald at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Brian Fitzgerald&lt;/a&gt; on September 12, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>